var chapters = [
  { chapter: 1, title: "Fundamentals of Strategic Management" },
  { chapter: 2, title: "Analysis of Industry and Competition" },
  { chapter: 3, title: "External Enviorment" },
  { chapter: 4, title: "Mission Objectives and Goals" },
  { chapter: 5, title: "chp  5 Corporate Level Strategy" },
];

var allQuestionAnswers = [
  {
    question:
      "Deepak, Head of Strategy Department at ABC Limited would like understand which of the following is least likely to lead to success of his organization?",
    options: [
      "Ability to execute the strategy",
      "Deviating from the strategic management process",
      "Stay focused on the target",
      "Constantly review the strategy and implementation process",
    ],
    answer: "Deviating from the strategic management process",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is least likely to be refined/ replaced frequently by the organization to address the changing market requirements?",
    options: [
      "CEO of the Company",
      "Strategies and structure",
      "Products and services",
      "Markets and competitive advantage",
    ],
    answer: "CEO of the Company",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is most likely to be important difference between Strategy and Strategic Management?",
    options: [
      "Strategic management requires analysis to be done before strategy formulation",
      "Strategic management requires analysis to be done after strategy implementation",
      "There is no difference between the two",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer:
      "Strategic management requires analysis to be done before strategy formulation",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is least likely to be an approach to strategic management as highlighted by Whittington?",
    options: ["Classical", "Processual", "Evolutionary", "Mysterious"],
    answer: "Mysterious",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following steps the organization is least likely to take after identification of its strengths and weaknesses?",
    options: [
      "Leverage the weaknesses",
      "Overcome the weaknesses",
      "Build inclusiveness",
      "Leverage the strengths",
    ],
    answer: "Leverage the weaknesses",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is most likely to be a reason for failure organizations in spite of having a robust strategic management process",
    options: [
      "Discipline",
      "Governance",
      "Over ambitious strategies",
      "Review and monitoring of process",
    ],
    answer: "Over ambitious strategies",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is least likely to be an outcome of the strategic management process?",
    options: [
      "Does ensure unconditional success",
      "Leads to an evolved framework",
      "Ensures risks are minimized",
      "Provide good perspective to management based on analysis of facts",
    ],
    answer: "Does ensure unconditional success",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is most likely to be a new world economy company?",
    options: [
      "IT and Internet",
      "Aviation",
      "Consumer electronics",
      "Automobile",
    ],
    answer: "IT and Internet",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following strategies are most likely to work for an organization which may take their own paths?",
    options: [
      "Cost focused",
      "Value focused",
      "Both 1 and 2",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Both 1 and 2",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Aman, new joiner in Strategy Function of GHT Limited confused and unable to identify which of the following is not a strategic decision. Assist him to identify the appropriate one?",
    options: [
      "Choosing the right market segment",
      "Purchase of vehicle for CEO’s use",
      "Developing the right products and services",
      "Creation of partner ecosystem",
    ],
    answer: "Purchase of vehicle for CEO’s use",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is most likely to help an organization to faster decision making to support the business and its stakeholders?",
    options: [
      "Responsibility Matrix",
      "Delegation of Authority Matrix",
      "Reporting Matrix",
      "Order approval matrix",
    ],
    answer: "Delegation of Authority Matrix",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Strategic Business Unit (SBU) is most likely to take the following strategic decision?",
    options: [
      "What businesses are we in?",
      "How do we compete?",
      "How do we support business level strategy",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "How do we compete?",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Dia, Head of Operations at GTF Limited is of the view that the top decision makers in an organization must understand the complex the relationship between the various factors across the business spectrum to take timely decisions and create actions. True or False?",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Corporate Strategy is the ___________ term strategy encompassing the entire organization",
    options: ["Long", "Medium", "Short", "Near"],
    answer: "Long",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Prudent business decision help organization to _______",
    options: [
      "Conserve resources",
      "Not get tempted to explore uncharted territory",
      "Not ending up underperforming versus set objectives",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is least likely to impact the company strategy?",
    options: [
      "Government policies",
      "Number of Functional Heads with Competitor",
      "Regulatory guidelines",
      "Industry body initiatives",
    ],
    answer: "Number of Functional Heads with Competitor",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Dhiren, a new joiner is of the view that the Porter’s model addresses the behavior of the organizations in an industry but does not account for the role of partnerships or alliances, which is a growing phenomenon today in many industries. true or false?",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following aspects is most likely to be addressed by Michael Porter’s competitive forces model?",
    options: [
      "Behavior of the organizations in an industry",
      "Steps taken by large players to change the structure of Industry",
      "Firms resources constitute the primary determinants",
      "Complex relations the firm create in the industry",
    ],
    answer: "Behavior of the organizations in an industry",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Each player in the markets comes with _____________________ which could cause shift in market positioning",
    options: [
      "Power levels of expertise",
      "Relative size of operations",
      "Both 1 and 2",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Both 1 and 2",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_______________ is very significant and evident in the industries like telecom, credit cards, internet services.",
    options: [
      "Customer churn",
      "Customer loyalty",
      "High price of services",
      "Differences in service quality",
    ],
    answer: "Customer churn",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "AMB Limited is working on to devise a strategy to engage the customer and ensure customer retention to sustain the business. Which of the following strategies is least likely to be help to AMB Limited?",
    options: [
      "Value proposition",
      "Customer loyalty programs",
      "Reducing the quantity of product for same price",
      "Adding value to the service at same price",
    ],
    answer: "Reducing the quantity of product for same price",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "____________ is the first step in the strategic analysis of an organization.",
    options: [
      "Implementation",
      "Formulation",
      "Industry Analysis",
      "Strategy monitoring and review",
    ],
    answer: "Industry Analysis",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Amit, Head of Strategy is worried out the decline in the industry sectors in which his company operates. Please help him to identify areas in strategy making which are least likely to help him to address the problem?",
    options: [
      "Sense change in trends",
      "Devising new strategies for transform",
      "Recreation of industry",
      "Maintain status quo",
    ],
    answer: "Maintain status quo",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "ABC Limited, a company producing computers, is keen to divest their business units and pursue new and innovative products and services to sustain in the business. Which of the following stage is ABC limited most likely to be?",
    options: [
      "Maturity state",
      "Decline stage",
      "Shakeout-stage",
      "Growth stage",
    ],
    answer: "Decline stage",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following statement is most likely to be true about visionaries?",
    options: [
      "Always stay ahead",
      "Come up with innovative ideas",
      "May lack execution capabilities",
      "Constantly look at new territories to grow",
    ],
    answer: "May lack execution capabilities",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_____________ is a very important strategic tool for IT players to analyze and formulate their industry strategies",
    options: [
      "Porter’s magic",
      "Gartner’s magic quadrant",
      "Deming’s PDCA cycle",
      "Six Sigma Quality Assurance process",
    ],
    answer: "Gartner’s magic quadrant",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Dinesh, a new joiner at Strategy Function of GFR Limited is of the view that strategic managers must use relevant analytical tools as appropriate for their industry to draw important strategic decisions for their organizations. true or false?",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is least likely to be reason for exit of industry players from the market in the situation of hyper competition?",
    options: [
      "High level of fixed costs",
      "High prices of the end product in the market",
      "High level of operating costs",
      "High debt servicing costs",
    ],
    answer: "High prices of the end product in the market",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is least expected to impact the market and the competition landscape?",
    options: [
      "The entry of new players",
      "Change in technology",
      "Change in consumer preferences and taste",
      "Launch of a new product variant by one of the competitor",
    ],
    answer: "Launch of a new product variant by one of the competitor",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "__________ is a structured way of capturing the different dynamics that play into an industry",
    options: [
      "Pest Control",
      "PEST Analysis",
      "Porter’s model",
      "Analysis of competition",
    ],
    answer: "PEST Analysis",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The industries and the markets across the world are seamless connected with ____________ entered between different countries which have trade relationships",
    options: [
      "Free Trade Agreements",
      "Restrictive Trade Agreements",
      "Anti-dumping contracts",
      "Military service agreements",
    ],
    answer: "Free Trade Agreements",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Aman, Head of Corporate Strategy at GYT Limited is of the opinion that the strategic managers need to seek to enable an organization to operate effectively within largely uncontrollable environmental constraints while capitalizing on the opportunities presented by the environment. true or false",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "ABC Limited is concerned about the political and legal forces which may impact its business. Which of the following aspects are least likely to be political and legal forces?",
    options: [
      "Outcome of elections",
      "New legislations",
      "Price changes by the competitor",
      "Judicial / court decision",
    ],
    answer: "Price changes by the competitor",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following policy is least likely to have an impact on the business of ABT Limited, a player in the cotton textile industry?",
    options: [
      "Industrial policy",
      "Fiscal policy",
      "Egg production council initiative",
      "Tariff policy",
    ],
    answer: "Egg production council initiative",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "___________ is the global international organization dealing with the rules of trade between nations",
    options: ["PATO", "WTO", "CEO", "CTO"],
    answer: "WTO",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Ketan, new joiner in strategy function of ABC Limited is keen to evaluate the role of regulator in the Business. Which of the following is least likely to be the role?",
    options: [
      "Formulation of policies to provide business permissions",
      "Promote monopoly in the industry",
      "Enhance the legal framework",
      "Facilitate industry development initiatives",
    ],
    answer: "Promote monopoly in the industry",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Under __________ programs banks are mandated to offer financial services to the unbanked population and each village is to be covered by a banking outlet.",
    options: [
      "Financial Inclusion",
      "Financial Exclusion",
      "Financial Explosion",
      "Financial Regulation",
    ],
    answer: "Financial Inclusion",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following are key economic forces affecting the strategy in an industry?",
    options: [
      "Liberalization of economy",
      "Economic development policies",
      "Open market approach",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______________ refers to the value of the country’s total production of goods and services.",
    options: ["EDP", "PDP", "GDP", "SDP"],
    answer: "GDP",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "A consistent GDP growth is fuelled by_____",
    options: [
      "Decrease in consumer spending",
      "Increase in consumer spending",
      "Healthy exports in international markets",
      "High productivity",
    ],
    answer: "Increase in consumer spending",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A rapid growing economy is all the time beneficial to the country.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The sale of product for which the demand is income_________ naturally increases with an increase in the income.",
    options: ["Inelastic", "Elastic", "Both 1 and 2", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Elastic",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The ultimate purpose of an organization is to create value for its office bearers at the cost of the value for stakeholders",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following means will help achievement of the organization’s vision?",
    options: [
      "Establishment of vision and objectives",
      "Communication of vision to its entire organization",
      "Integrate the view of various stakeholders",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_______ are those ends which the organization seeks to achieve by its existence and operations",
    options: ["Objectives", "Profit", "Assets", "Liabilities"],
    answer: "Objectives",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is least likely to be true about Vision of an organization?",
    options: [
      "Value statement that reflects the principle of organization",
      "Is short term in nature",
      "Pivot around which the corporate strategy revolves",
      "Define the purpose of an organization",
    ],
    answer: "Is short term in nature",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Amit, COO of GYT Limited is of the view that defining the purpose and mission of the business is difficult, hence the vision and mission need not be defined as it is waste of time. true or false?",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is least likely to be a quality or characteristics of a vision and mission statement?",
    options: [
      "Identified the scope of company’s operations",
      "Enduring statement of purpose that matches one business from other similar firms",
      "Shapes customer understanding of why they should work with the company",
      "Shared with the customers and partners",
    ],
    answer:
      "Enduring statement of purpose that matches one business from other similar firms",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Suman, a new joiner in corporate strategy function of GTF Limited if of the view that, a mission statement is often expressed at high levels of abstraction, because they are designed to express concrete end and provide motivation, general direction. true or false?",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "To create the mission statement, the organization need to first identify________",
    options: [
      "Its purpose",
      "A winning idea",
      "Objective that helps organization’s purpose",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Its purpose",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following a mission statement is least likely to do for organization?",
    options: [
      "Sets the direction for strategy development of an organization",
      "Make organization to wander around and divert focus from action",
      "Helps in creating disciplined organization",
      "Define specific strategies need to attain the crucial goals",
    ],
    answer: "Make organization to wander around and divert focus from action",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Deepak, Head of Strategy at GYT Limited is of the view that strategy determines the direction and scope of an organization over a longer term it should determine how resources should be configured to meet the needs of markets. true or false?",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Since organization has overall strategy, it is futile to formulate Business Unit and Functional Strategy",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is least likely to be characteristics of objectives?",
    options: [
      "Get reflected as the strategy keep evolving",
      "Objectives need to be static in nature",
      "Clearly established at the corporate and unit level",
      "Consider the changes in the external and internal environment",
    ],
    answer: "Objectives need to be static in nature",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is most likely to be a key objective of financial institutions with respect to a large corporate?",
    options: [
      "Maximum profitability for the company",
      "Long term serviceability of the debt",
      "Highest remuneration levels to the CEO",
      "Large customer base",
    ],
    answer: "Long term serviceability of the debt",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "While organization acquires other companies either in the same line of business or unrelated line of business, there are challenges in terms of _______ of the new companies with the core business.",
    options: [
      "Integration",
      "Disintegration",
      "Diversification",
      "Segregation",
    ],
    answer: "Integration",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "ABC Limited has acquired GTY Limited and both the companies are in Textile Business. The team is managing the horizontal integration. Which of the following is least likely to be outcome through the integration?",
    options: [
      "Enhanced market share by addition",
      "Expansion into new geographic markets",
      "Erosion of purchasing power",
      "Leverage synergies to enhance margins",
    ],
    answer: "Erosion of purchasing power",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Harish, CEO of ABC Limited is evaluating proposal for vertical integration. He is identifying the probable disadvantage related to this proposal. Please help him to identify which of the following is least likely to be a disadvantage?",
    options: [
      "Inability to achieve reduction in cost of sourcing",
      "Reduces operational flexibility",
      "May lead to increased cost for want of production volume",
      "Overhead costs may increase significantly",
    ],
    answer: "Inability to achieve reduction in cost of sourcing",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Girish, Head of Strategy with GTY Limited is of the view that, the success of integration is lies in choosing the right fit and identifying the right strategy. true or false?",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In which of the following cases the strategic alliance is least likely to work?",
    options: [
      "Company’s growth strategy is based on finding best partner",
      "Company also interested in reinventing the wheel to build up expertise",
      "Objective is to achieve reduction in time to market and developmental costs",
      "Need is there for each other for success",
    ],
    answer:
      "Company also interested in reinventing the wheel to build up expertise",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following activity is least likely to be part of corporate restructuring exercise?",
    options: [
      "Retrenchment of people",
      "Alteration of management structure",
      "Merger and acquisition",
      "Divestment of unprofitable business units",
    ],
    answer: "Merger and acquisition",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Companies that do voluntary restructuring as necessary do not face the threat of hostile takeover due to poor performance and cheap valuation.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Corporate strategy is the ____________ strategy encompassing the entire organization",
    options: ["Medium term", "Near term", "Short term", "Long term"],
    answer: "Long term",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is least likely to be addressed by Corporate Strategy?",
    options: [
      "What is the purpose of the enterprise",
      "What business wants t pursue",
      "What are the priorities of the competitor so that organization can follow",
      "Define business guidelines and corporate governance",
    ],
    answer:
      "What are the priorities of the competitor so that organization can follow",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Corporate strategy is least likely to be formulated by _________",
    options: [
      "Chairman",
      "Board of Directors",
      "Chief Technology Officer",
      "Chief Executive Officer",
    ],
    answer: "Chief Technology Officer",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "ABC Limited’s top management deliberated on corporate strategy and came out with few options. Which of the following option according to you is most unsuitable for the well being of the Company?",
    options: [
      "To operate in a single industry",
      "To operate in completely unknown market and take very high risks",
      "To operate in multiple related industries",
      "To operate in multiple unrelated industries",
    ],
    answer: "To operate in completely unknown market and take very high risks",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following companies are susceptible to cyclical downturns and adverse changes in the macro environmental forces?",
    options: [
      "Single industry",
      "Multiple related industries",
      "Multiple unrelated industries",
      "Conglomerates",
    ],
    answer: "Single industry",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is most likely reason for organizations to diversify in one or more businesses or markets?",
    options: [
      "To become famous world over",
      "Insulate form cyclical downturns and explore new business areas",
      "CEO’s whims and fancies",
      "Request of the Board",
    ],
    answer: "Insulate form cyclical downturns and explore new business areas",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is least likely to be an outcome of diversification strategy?",
    options: [
      "Growth in revenues and profits",
      "Increased dependency on one business line",
      "Efficient use of resources",
      "Building of new products and services",
    ],
    answer: "Increased dependency on one business line",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Sanjay, Head of Merger is working on integration of two businesses to optimize the cost. Which of the following challenge is most likely to be difficult for Sanjay to resolve and address?",
    options: [
      "Different cost structure",
      "Business units do not share common cultural values",
      "Two business operate from different units",
      "Level of automations is different",
    ],
    answer: "Business units do not share common cultural values",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is not an inorganic growth strategy?",
    options: [
      "Vertical integration",
      "Growth in turnover and increased market share of the company",
      "Horizontal integration",
      "Merger and acquisition",
    ],
    answer: "Growth in turnover and increased market share of the company",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
];
